Finding Aid for Sam Sturgis Photograph collection
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
Sam Sturgis photograph collection 1860s-1970s
Sturgis, Sam, collector
92262 UA 2
Photographs collected by Sam Sturgis and Hazel Proctor of Ann Arbor, Michigan; including businesses, street scenes, buildings, people, and activities in Ann Arbor, Brighton, Chelsea, Dexter, Dixboro, Manchester, Saline, and Ypsilanti, Michigan. (Copy negatives and copy prints.)
10 linear feet 11 boxes including 1 oversize box
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
The collection was donated by Sam Sturgis beginning in 1966 (donor no. 4433 )
No further additions to the collection are expected.
All prints in the Sturgis collection are open for use without restriction. The negatives in boxes 6-8 are restricted to Bentley staff use for preservation purposes.
Sam Sturgis was an Ann Arbor Michigan photographer. He was also a collector of vintage and historical photographs relating to Ann Arbor and Ypsilanti, Michigan, and to other communities within Washtenaw County. He collected both original photographs and photoprints of originals. In addition, his collection includes original photographs taken by Sturgis of contemporary events and places.
The Sturgis collection consists of 11 boxes of photoprints and negatives. Boxes 1-5 contain copy prints, boxes 6-8 contain copy negatives and some original glass negatives, while boxes 9-11 contain oversized copy prints and a few original prints. The prints in boxes 9-11 will remain unnumbered and are organized by folder in general subject categories until time and staff are available for additional arrangement and description.
Summary Container List
ANN ARBOR SERIES
Photographs AA 1A -AA 221.36 -- Box One
Photographs AA 222 -AA 264D -- Box Two
Photographs AA 265 -AA 503.5 -- Box Three
Photographs AA 504.1 -AA 789 -- Box Four
Negatives AA 1 -AA 282.1 -- Box Six
Negatives AA 282.2 -AA 789 -- Box Seven
Unnumbered photographs in 11 folders -- Box Nine
AA businesses, buildings, scenic views, trains, soldiers and U of M.
Unnumbered oversized photographs in 4 folders -- Box Ten
AA streets and businesses, scenic views, U of M group and individual portraits.
Unnumbered photographs in 3 folders -- Box Eleven
AA street and construction scenes from 1930s, 1960s and 1970s.
BRIGHTON SERIES
All photographs -- Box Five
All negatives -- Box Seven
CHELSEA SERIES
All photographs -- Box Five
Negatives C 1 -C 25.12 -- Box Seven
Negatives C 25.13 -CM 52 -- Box Eight
DEXTER SERIES
All photographs -- Box Five
All negatives -- Box Eight
DIXBORO SERIES
All photographs -- Box Five
All negatives -- Box Eight
MANCHESTER SERIES
All photographs -- Box Five
All negatives -- Box Eight
SALINE SERIES
All photographs -- Box Five
All negatives -- Box Eight
YPSILANTI SERIES
All photographs -- Box Five
All negatives -- Box Eight
Boxes 5-7 contain negatives of the photographs in the collection and are only for staff use.
The Sam Sturgis collection consists of photographic prints and copy negatives of Washtenaw and Livingston County life from the 1860s through the 1970s. Collected by Ann Arbor photographer Sam Sturgis and Ypsilanti banker Hazel Proctor from a variety of known and unknown sources, the collection represents many aspects of life in Ann Arbor, Brighton, Chelsea, Dexter, Dixboro, Manchester, Saline and Ypsilanti. Main subject categories include churches, schools, businesses, buildings, University of Michigan buildings, staff, students and campus life, streets, panoramic views, rivers, recreation and family life, including residences, men, women, and children. Evolving modes of transportation, such as railroads, interurban streetcars, automobiles, and airplanes are also depicted.
Prints and negatives are divided into two parallel series, with negative use restricted to Bentley staff for preservation and security purposes. Each series is arranged alphabetically by city or town and, within each geographical grouping, in the order in which Sturgis collected the items. Sturgis began donating his collection to the Bentley in 1966, and, as items continue to be received, numbering is continued within each geographical grouping, in the original collecting and numbering order established by Sturgis. While some numbers were originally intended by Sturgis to designate the origins of the item, if known, this information has also been added to the item description under the heading "source" to facilitate patron and staff use. The Bentley does not hold a complete set of prints and negatives. Information on the current availability of both prints and negatives is included in each item listing.
Each photograph has a unique identifying number. The "Sturgis Number" consists of a one or two-letter series code, followed by a numerical number with decimal or alphanumeric number, such as AA 267.21 or AA 35A. the collection is arranged by city as follows
Ann Arbor AA ca. 1500
Brighton BB 148
Chelsea C 156
Chelsea-Manchester CM 119
Dexter D 124
Dixboro DI 45
Manchester M 123
Saline S 57
Ypsilanti Y 150
An item list of all photographs with description, date (if known), source and photographer, if known, follows the summary contents list on page three of the introduction.
Information on whether the photograph has been published and therefore has further information provided elsewhere is also included in each item description. Unless otherwise noted, all photographs listed as "published" have been published in a series by the Ann Arbor Federal Savings Bank (AAFSB), with editorial supervision by Sam Sturgis and Hazel Proctor. Availability of the respective print and negative concludes each item entry.
The following books, published by the AAFSB in the early 1970s, are annotated with Sturgis' photograph numbers and may be used as a partial guide to the collection. While two copies of each publication are available for consultation in the reading room, only one of each set has annotations. Descriptive captions in these publications as well as the annotated numbers may differ from actual photograph numbers and other information about the photographs. Any reference to these annotations should be verified with the item lists and vice versa to assure accuracy because of occasional inconsistencies. The AAFSB publications with Bentley call numbers are listed as follows:
Proctor, Hazel. Old Ann Arbor Town. 1974. Copy 1 annotated. EC 2 A216.5 P964
Sam Sturgis. Memories of Old Ann Arbor Town, 1967. Copies 1 and 2 annotated. EC 2 A613.5 S935
Proctor, Hazel. Old Brighton Village. 1974. Copy 1 annotated. EC 2 B856.3 P964
Proctor, Hazel. Old Chelsea Village. 1972. Copy 2 annotated. EC2 C516.5 P964
Proctor, Hazel. Old Dexter Village. 1973. Copy 1 annotated. EC 2 D526.5 P964
Proctor, Hazel. Old Manchester Village. 1974. Copy 2 annotated. EC 2 M268.5 P964
Proctor, Hazel. Old Saline Village. 1975. Copy 1 annotated. EC 2 S165.5 P964
Proctor, Hazel. Old Ypsilanti Town. 1974. Copy 2 annotated. EC 2 Y86.5 P964
Subjects - Visual Materials:
Agriculture.; Ann Arbor (Mich.)--Buildings.; Ann Arbor (Mich.)--Business enterprises.; Ann Arbor Art Fairs (Ann Arbor, Mich.); Ann Arbor (Mich.)--Dwellings.; Ann Arbor (Mich.)--Streets.; Service stations.; Bands.; Brighton (Mich.); Business enterprises.; Business enterprises--Michigan--Ann Arbor.; Chelsea (Mich.); Churches.; Dexter (Mich.); Dixboro (Mich.); Dwellings.; Dwellings--Michigan--Ann Arbor.; Eastern Michigan University.; Farms.; Fire engines and equipment.; Fires.; Huron River (Oakland County-Monroe County, Mich.); Manchester (Mich.); Mills.; Musicians.; Parades and processions.; Railroad accidents.; Saline (Mich.); Schools--Michigan--Washtenaw County.; Soldiers--American--Michigan--Washtenaw County.; Sports.; Streets--Michigan--Ann Arbor.; University of Michigan--Buildings.; University of Michigan--Campus.; University of Michigan--Students--Social life and customs.; Ypsilanti (Mich.)
Contributors:
Proctor, Hazel, collector.
Genre Terms:
Photographs.
- Ann Arbor
  - AA 1 - AA 100
    - Ann Arbor Railroad derailment "out Miller Avenue" in 1893. 1893, AA 1A -; Copy neg. na 15,533 (Box 1)
      (Source: CT Stoner.)
    - Ann Arbor Railroad derailment "out Miller Avenue" in 1893. 1893, AA 1B -; Copy neg. (Box 1)
    - West Physics building on South University Ave., UM campus., AA 2.1 -; Glass neg. (Box 1)
    - UM Tappan Hall in 1894. 1894, AA 2.2 -; Glass neg. (Box 1)
    - UM Waterman Gymnasium on 27 Oct. 1897. 1897, AA 2.3 -; Glass neg. (Box 1)
    - UM Waterman Gymnasium in 1897. 1897, AA 2.4 -; Glass neg. (Box 1)
    - UM Medical Building., AA 2.5 -; Glass neg. (Box 1)
    - UM Engineering Shops., AA 2.6 -; Glass neg. (Box 1)
    - UM Museum, later the Romance Language Building., AA 2.7 -; Glass neg. (Box 1)
    - UM Dental School., AA 2.8 -; copy neg na 12,221 (Box 1)
    - UM Law Building c. 1895. circa 1895, AA 2.9 -; Glass neg. & Copy neg. (Box 1)
    - UM Power Plant., AA 2.10 -; Glass neg. (Box 1)
    - UM Dental School Building., AA 2.11 -; copy neg na 12,222 (Box 1)
    - UM Newberry Hall., AA 2.12 -; Glass neg. (Box 1)
    - Engineering building on South University Ave with West Physics building on left. East of present site of Clements Library., AA 2.13 -; Glass neg. (Box 1)
    - UM Engineering Building on South University Ave. East of present site of Clements Library., AA 2.14 -; Glass neg. (Box 1)
    - Chemistry Building in the 1890s, later Pharmacy Building. circa 1890, AA 2.15 -; Glass neg. (Box 1)
    - Campus restroom entitled "Campus Beauty.", AA 2.16 -; Glass neg. (Box 1)
    - Campus restroom., AA 2.17 -; Glass neg. (Box 1)
      ([Dew drop Inn]
    - UM Anatomy Laboratory in 1887. 1887, AA 2.18 -; Glass neg. (Box 1)
    - Old UM Library, stood from 1883. Photo taken sometime between circa 1885-1917. 1900, AA 2.19 -; Glass neg., Copy neg. (Box 1)
    - UM Boiler House., AA 2.20 -; Glass neg. (Box 1)
    - Jimmie Ottley, "Coat or Hat (?) Man" at old UM Library, 15 December 1897. 1897, AA 2.21 -; Glass neg. (Box 1)
    - Henry Perfield, Dental College janitor, 1897. 1897, AA 2.22 -; Glass neg. (Box 1)
    - Parade in 1897. 1897, AA 2.23 -; Glass neg. (Box 1)
    - Dr. LP Hall, UM dental faculty in 1897. 1897, AA 2.24 -; Glass neg. (Box 1)
    - Photo entitled, "Doc" Naegle, UM Dental School c. 1900. circa 1900, AA 2.25 -; Glass neg. (Box 1)
    - UM baseball players in 1897. 1897, AA 2.26 -; Glass neg. Copy neg. (Box 1)
    - Start of UM track race in 1897. 1897, AA 2.27 -; Glass neg. (Box 1)
    - Residence., AA 2.28 -; Glass neg. (Box 1)
    - UM University Hall in 1897. 1897, AA 2.29 -; Glass neg. (Box 1)
    - Lecture room in UM Dental School, Dr. John H. Watling and students. December 1897. 1897, AA 2.30 -; copy neg na 12,223 (Box 1)
    - Students studying, Miss Hubbard in December 1897. 1897, AA 2.31 -; copy neg na 12,224 (Box 1)
    - Dental juniors in lecture room with Dr. Lyons on 15 Dec. 1897. 1897, AA 2.32 -; copy neg na 12,227 (Box 1)
    - Mail Carrier No. 10 on 10 Dec. 1897. 1897, AA 2.33 -; Glass neg. (Box 1)
    - UM President's House, 815 South University Avenue. Built 1840. US Register of Historic Places., AA 2.34 -; Glass neg. (Box 1)
    - UM Dental School display case of students' work. 10 Dec. 1897. 1897, AA 2.35 -; Glass neg. (Box 1)
    - Dr. Jonathan Taft, Dean of UM Dental School, 1875-1903., AA 2.36 -; Glass neg. Copy neg. (Box 1)
    - Dr. Jonathan Taft, Dean of UM Dental School, 1875-1903, in his office., AA 2.37 -; Glass neg. Copy neg. (Box 1)
    - UM Dental School Alumnus. Art Forbes is photographer and/or circa 1895, AA 2.38 -; Glass neg. (Box 1)
      (Source, c. 1890-1900.)
    - Man., AA 2.39 -; Glass neg. (Box 1)
    - Law Professor Horace Lafayette Wilgus and family inside home at 919 North University Avenue on 20 Nov. 1897. 1897, AA 2.40 -; Glass neg. (Box 1)
    - H.M. Heron and Pay A. Wagner on 14 October 1897. 1897, AA 2.41 -; Glass neg. (Box 1)
      (Source: George Wahr.)
    - Mrs. Horace Lafayette Wilgus and sons outside home on 919 North University Ave. on 3 Oct. 1897. 1897, AA 2.42 -; Glass neg. (Box 1)
    - UM student in bathtub in 1897. 1897, AA 2.43 -; copy neg na 12,225 (Box 1)
    - UM students in room. 1897, AA 2.44 -; copy neg na 12,226 (Box 1)
    - UM student Walter David studying at desk., AA 2.45 -; copy neg na 12,220 (Box 1)
    - UM student studying in 1897. 1897, AA 2.46 -; copy neg na 12,219 (Box 1)
    - Panoramic view of Ann Arbor from Chub Road (now Sunset) looking southeast, c. 1890. circa 1890, AA 3 -; Glass neg. Copy neg. (Box 1)
    - Ann Arbor High School in 1894. 1894, AA 4 -; Copy neg na 15,534 (Box 1)
    - Cousins and Hall flower delivery truck on Haven Street between Hill St. and South University Ave. looking north. John Hall may be, AA 5 -; Copy neg. [5x7] (Box 1)
      (Source and/or photographer.)
    - First Bethlehem United Church or Bethlehem Evangelical School. Pastor E.R. Klaudt. Located at 436 South First St. in 1908. 1908, AA 6 -; Copy neg. [5x7] (Box 1)
    - Interurban train wreck at the corner of Huron and Main Streets involving the Farmers and Mechanics Bank. August 1927, AA 7 -; Copy neg. (Box 1)
      (Source or photographer: Casey Samborski.)
      [See also AA-8 and 9.]
    - 1927, AA 8 -; Copy neg. [5x7] (Box 1)
      [See also AA-7 and 9]
    - See also AA-7 and 8. 1927, AA 9 -; Copy neg. [5x7] (Box 1)
    - East Main St. looking north before 1908, from early postcard. circa 1900, AA 10 -; Copy neg. [5x7] (Box 1)
    - Parade and courthouse on Main St. c. 1880. circa 1880, AA 11 -; Copy neg. [5x7] (Box 1)
      (Source and/or Photographer: Bob Shaw, Ypsi.)
    - Group picture "Vigilant Hose Co." Fire Dept, between 1884 and 1887, possibly 1880. AAFD. circa 1885, AA 12 -; copy neg na 15,535 (Box 1)
    - Construction of Nickels Arcade looking West. Photographer and/or 1916, AA 13 -; Copy neg. (Box 1)
      (Five negs., each a different shot of Maynard and State Sts. in 1916. Source: Pete Van Boven.)
    - Independence Day celebration at corner of Huron and Main Sts. near courthouse. Copied from a stereopticon., AA 14 -; Copy neg. [5x7] (Box 1)
      (Source and/or photographer: Mrs. Grooms.)
    - Early view of Main Street showing Mack and Co. and looking northwest c. 1905. circa 1905, AA 15 --; copy neg na 13,900 (Box 1)
      [See also AA-128]
    - Construction of Nickels Arcade looking west from State St. on 2 Sept. 1915. 1915, AA 16 --; Copy neg. (Box 1)
      (Source or photographer: John Cole.)
    - Employees of Luick Lumber Company (now Kerrytown and Farmer's Market). Could be as early as 1885. Front row center: Emanuel and Gottlieb Luick, owners. Photographer and/or circa 1890, AA 17 --; copy neg. na 15,536 (Box 1)
      (Source: Waldo Luick.)
    - Employees of Luick Lumber, as early as 1895. First row right: Emanuel Luick. Top row right: Gottlieb Luick. Seated: Albert Luick/ Top row left: Gottlieb Luick's Son. circa 1895, AA 18 --; Copy neg. [5x7] (Box 1)
    - Decoration Day float in front of Luick Lumber Co. in 1895. 1895, AA 19 --; Copy neg. [5x7] na 15,920 (Box 1)
      (On Detroit St. and Fifth Ave. with Walker Carriage Factory on corner at left.)
    - Decoration Day float at the corner of Detroit and Fifth Streets c. 1895. Walker Carriage Factory is at the far left. 1895, AA 20 --; Copy neg. [5x7] na 15,921 (Box 1)
    - James Tom's Greenhouse at corner of Miller and Chapin Streets about 1882-1883. 1882, AA 21 --; Copy neg. [5x7] na 15,537 (Box 1)
      (Mrs. Davenport from Saline in dark dress. Source or photographer: Alfred W. Goodhew.)
    - Scenic view of AA from Cedar Bend Drive., AA 22A -- (Box 1)
      (Source: Donald Exinger.)
    - Michigan Central Railroad depot., AA 22B --; Copy neg. [5x7] (Box 1)
    - The Fair Store., AA 22C --; Copy neg. [5x7] (Box 1)
    - Island Park concession stands., AA 22D --; Copy neg. [5x7] (Box 1)
    - Varsity Laundry 217 South Fourth Ave, from 1903 postcard. 1903, AA 23 --; [Copy neg. [5x7] (Box 1)
      (Source: Dalitz.)
    - Camp Birkitt group of scouts in 1917. 1917, AA 24 --; Copy neg. [5x7] (Box 1)
      (Source: Cliff Westerman.)
    - Ann Arbor Fire department in front of Engine House., AA 25 --; Copy neg. [5x7] (Box 1)
      (Source: Hanselman.)
    - Van's Marine Band in 1916. (Sponsored by Van's Restaurant.) 1916, AA 26A --; Copy neg. [5x7] na 11,174 (Box 1)
      (Source: Berle Walker.)
    - Panoramic view looking west on Liberty St. in 1910. circa 1910, AA 26B --; copy neg. na 15,538 (Box 1)
      (Source: Berle Walker. Adelbert Walker in center.)
    - Walker's Livery Cutter, horse-drawn. Mr. Lew Hammond, driver. circa 1910, AA 26C --; Copy neg. [5x7] (Box 1)
    - Walker's Livery, 515 E. Liberty St. in 1910. Charles Alexander on left. Adelbert Walker in center. circa 1910, AA 26D --; [5x7] (Box 1)
    - Red Top Cab, taxi service., AA 26E --; Copy neg. [5x7] (Box 1)
    - American House Hotel, 121 West Washington St., AA 27 --; Copy neg. [5x7] (Box 1)
      (Source: Mrs. Al Nue. Photographer: Reuenaugh and Co.)
    - Ann Arbor Fire Department near Chapin St. in 1908. 1908, AA 27A --; Copy neg. [5x7] (Box 1)
    - 3rd Ward School at Miller and Fountain Sts. (now entrance to West Park)., AA 27B --; Copy neg. [5x7] (Box 1)
    - W.S.A. Gwinner, Porter Zouave Band, August 1869, AA 27C --; Copy neg. [5x7] (Box 1)
    - R.C. Traver, Porter Zouave Band, August 1869, AA 27D --; Copy neg. [5x7] (Box 1)
    - C. Jacob Gwinner, Porter Zouave Band, August 1869, AA 27E --; Copy neg. [5x7] (Box 1)
    - Map of Ann Arbor from 1874, Washtenaw County Atlas, Bob Klinger 1874, AA 28A --; Copy neg. [5x7] (Box 1)
      (Source or photographer?. Section (3rd Ward) of the northern half of Ann Arbor.)
    - Map of Ann Arbor from 1874, Washtenaw County Atlas, Bob Klinger 1874, AA 28B --; Copy neg. [5x7] (Box 1)
      (Source or photographer. Section (4th and 5th Wards) of the northern half of Ann Arbor.)
    - Map of Ann Arbor from 1874, Washtenaw County Atlas, Bob Klinger 1874, AA 28C --; Copy neg. [5x7] (Box 1)
      (Source or photographer. Section (2nd Ward) of the southern half of Ann Arbor.)
    - Map of Ann Arbor from 1874, Washtenaw County Atlas, Bob Klinger 1874, AA 28D --; Copy neg. No print. [5x7] (Box 1)
      (Source or photographer. Section (1st and 6th Wards) of the southern half of Ann Arbor.)
    - Looking north from the Courthouse tower showing undeveloped land. Photo from the Olmsted Brother planning report to the City Council and Chamber of Commerce ca. 1921. 1922, AA 29A --; Copy neg. [5x7] (Box 1)
      (Source-Photographer: Swain)
    - Michigan Central RR depot; built 1886 at cost of $33,000. From the Olmsted Brother planning report to the City Council and Chamber of Commerce, 1921. Photo taken c. 1915. circa 1915, AA 29B --; Copy neg. [5x7] na 16,061 (Box 1)
      (Swain photo.)
    - North Main St. scene at Whitmore Lake Road and the Ann Arbor RR tracks in 1921. From the Olmsted Brother planning report to the City Council and Chamber of Commerce, c. 1921. 1921, AA 29C --; Copy neg. [5x7] (Box 1)
    - From the Olmsted Brother planning report to the City Council and Chamber of Commerce, c. 1921. Glen and Catherine Sts. looking to Huron Valley. 1921, AA 29D --; Copy neg. Published. [5x7] (Box 1)
    - Southeast view from Courthouse tower toward Old Zion Church. From the Olmsted Brother planning report to the City Council and Chamber of Commerce, c. 1921. circa 1915, AA 29E --; Copy neg. [5x7] (Box 1)
      (Photo taken c. 1915. Swain photo.)
    - East view from courthouse. From the Olmsted Brother planning report to the City Council and Chamber of Commerce, c.1921. Photo taken 1915. circa 1915, AA 29F --; Copy neg. [5x7] (Box 1)
    - Looking north from the courthouse. Fourth Ave. and Detroit Sts. From the Olmsted Brother planning report to the City Council and Chamber of Commerce, c. 1921. Photo includes Foerster Hotel, White Swan Laundry, Wurster Bros. Creamery. Copy Swain. [5x7] circa 1921, AA 29G -- (Box 1)
    - Looking east on West William St. from South First St. From the Olmsted planning report to the Chamber of Commerce and City Council, c. 1921. Photo taken c. 1915. 1915, AA 29H --; Copy neg. [5x7] (Box 1)
    - View up the existing Pontiac Trail From the Olmsted planning report to the City Council and Chamber of Commerce, c. 1921. Photo taken c. 1915. circa 1915, AA 29I --; Copy neg. [5x7] na 13,078 (Box 1)
      (Published. Swain photo.)
    - River valley north of the University Hospital on Geddes Road in 1921. From the Olmsted planning report to the City Council and Chamber of Commerce, c. 1921. 1921, AA 29J --; Copy neg. [5x7] (Box 1)
    - View up the river from Long Shore Drive. From the Olmsted Brother planning report to the City Council and Chamber of Commerce c. 1920. circa 1920, AA 29K --; Copy neg. [5x7] (Box 1)
    - Southeast on Pontiac Trail at the corner of Cedar St. "Lower" town. From the Olmsted Brother planning report to the City Council and Chamber of Commerce, c. 1921. circa 1921, AA 29L --; Copy neg. [5x7] (Box 1)
    - Looking up Wall St. to its junction with Broadway. From the Olmsted Brother planning report to the City Council and Chamber of Commerce, c. 1921. Photo c. 1915. circa 1915, AA 29M --; Copy neg. [5x7] (Box 1)
    - Looking west from the Courthouse Tower. Old West Side, between 1917 and 1922. 1917, AA 29N --; Copy neg. [5x7] (Box 1)
    - Depot St. looking west from the Broadway Bridge, 1922. From the Olmsted Brother planning report to the City Council and Chamber of Commerce, c. 1921. circa 1920, AA 29O --; Copy neg. [5x7] (Box 1)
    - Looking northwest from the Courthouse, 1917. From the Olmsted Brother planning report to the City Council and Chamber of Commerce, c. 1921. Photo taken in 1917. Photographer: Swain. 1917, AA 29P --; Copy neg. I5x7] (Box 1)
      (Including West Park, Miller St and Hotel Whitney.)
    - Duplicate of 29A. circa 1920, AA 29Q --; No print or neg. except AA-29A. [5x7] (Box 1)
      (Photographer: Swain.)
    - Looking southwest from the Courthouse. From the Olmsted Brother planning report to the City Council and Chamber of Commerce, c. 1921. Photo taken in 1917. Photographer: Swain. 1917, AA 29R --; Copy neg. [5x7] (Box 1)
    - Looking northeast from the Courthouse. From the Olmsted Brother planning report to the City Council and Chamber of Commerce, c. 1921. Photo taken in 1917. Photographer: Swain. 1917, AA 29S --; Copy neg. na 13,042 (Box 1)
    - View of buildings on Broadway. From the Olmsted Brother planning report to the City Council and Chamber of Commerce, c. 1921. Photo c. 1915. Photographer: Swain. circa 1915, AA 29T --; Copy neg. [5x7] (Box 1)
      (Located opposite Broadway with Washtenaw Hotel at left.)
    - Map of Ann Arbor, 1866 or 1875? circa 1870, AA 30 --; Copy neg. na 13,496 (Box 1)
      (Source: Mrs. Pardon.)
    - Wagner's store on 121 South Main St. with bicycle in window in 1883 or 1890. circa 1885, AA 31A --; Copy neg. na 15,539 (Box 1)
      (Source: Wagner.)
    - Men's bicycle club on the front steps of the Courthouse, 1880s. circa 1880, AA 31B --; Copy neg. na 11,171 (Box 1)
    - Michigan Beef and Provision store on S. State St. during early 1900s. circa 1900, AA 32A --; Copy neg. [5x7] (Box 1)
      (Source: Bea Nickels.)
    - Interior of S.B. Nickels Meat Market in 1909 on 607 East William St. 1909, AA 32B --; Copy neg. na 15,540 (Box 1)
    - Exterior of 332 South State St., AA 32C --; Copy neg. [5x7] (Box 1)
    - Exterior of J.H. Nickels Meat Market at 26 S. State St. 1872, AA 32D --; Copy neg. [5x7] (Box 1)
    - North University Ave. looking east from State St., AA 32E --; Copy neg. (Box 1)
    - S.B. Nickels portrait., AA 32F --; Copy neg. (Box 1)
    - Derailment of the New York Central Railroad at Ann Arbor Railroad depot in 1941. 1941, AA 33 --; Copy neg. [5x7] (Box 1)
    - B. St. James Store at 126 North Main St. 1909, AA 34A --; Copy neg. [5x7] (Box 1)
      (Bruno St. James sold store to Bertha Muehlig. Source: Ray Hutzel.)